<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dall%3ACartan%20geometry%20unification%20torsion%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D5" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=all:Cartan geometry unification torsion&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=5</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/8C7yRSg9ItGTkLPbIiupb2EsFXM</id>
  <updated>2025-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">224139</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">5</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1302.3255v1</id>
    <updated>2013-02-11T14:46:19Z</updated>
    <published>2013-02-11T14:46:19Z</published>
    <title>Finsler Metrics with Bounded Cartan Torsions</title>
    <summary>  The norm of Cartan torsion plays an important role for studying of immersion
theory in Finsler geometry. Indeed, Finsler manifold with unbounded Cartan
torsion can not be isometrically imbedded into any Minkowski space. In this
paper, we find two subclasses of (?, ?)-metrics which have bounded Cartan
torsion. Then, we give two subclasses of (?, ?)-metrics whose bound on the
Cartan torsions are independent of the norm of ?.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>A. Tayebi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>H. Sadeghi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>E. Peyghan</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1302.3255v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1302.3255v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="math.DG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.DG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="53C60, 53C25" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.03165v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-05T07:10:57Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-05T07:10:57Z</published>
    <title>On the Cartan torsion of Minkowskian product of Finsler manifolds</title>
    <summary>  In this paper, we investigate the Cartan torsion and mean Cartan torsion of
the Minkowskian product of two Finsler metrics. We derive explicit formulas for
both torsions and analyze their geometric behavior. In particular, we
demonstrate that both the Cartan torsion and mean Cartan torsion decompose
additively if and only if the Minkowskian product is Euclidean. Additionally,
we provide a necessary and sufficient condition for the norm of the mean Cartan
torsion to remain bounded in the Euclidean case.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ranadip Gangopadhyay</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.03165v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.03165v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="math.DG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.DG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="53B40, 53C60" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1204.5951v3</id>
    <updated>2012-06-24T23:42:04Z</updated>
    <published>2012-04-26T14:53:32Z</published>
    <title>Dirac and Generalized Complex Structures on Cartan Geometries</title>
    <summary>  We introduce linear Dirac and generalized complex structures on Cartan
geometries and give criteria for Dirac subalgebras of $\frkg\ltimes\frkg^*$
representing Dirac structures on a Cartan geometry. We prove that there is a
bijection between the linear generalized structures on a torsion free Cartan
geometry and the equivariant generalized structures on its corresponding
homogeneous space.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Honglei Lang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xiaomeng Xu</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">12 pages</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1204.5951v3" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1204.5951v3" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="math.DG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.DG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/gr-qc/9808004v1</id>
    <updated>1998-08-03T08:47:37Z</updated>
    <published>1998-08-03T08:47:37Z</published>
    <title>Einstein-Cartan-Maxwell Theory with Scalar Field through a
  Five-Dimensional Unification</title>
    <summary>  A modification of Kaluza-Klein theory is proposed in which, as a result of a
symmetry breaking, five-dimensional space-time is partially parallelized
implying the appearance of torsion fields. A naturally chosen action functional
leads to the Einstein-Cartan-Maxwell theory where the electromagnetic field
strength is represented by the fifth component of the torsion 2-form.
Incorporation of a scalar field reveals that four-dimensional space-time
torsion is not induced by the scalar field.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>C. Kohler</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:doi xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">10.1142/S0217751X00000562</arxiv:doi>
    <link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1142/S0217751X00000562" rel="related"/>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">6 pages, REVTeX</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:journal_ref xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Int.J.Mod.Phys. A15 (2000) 1235-1244</arxiv:journal_ref>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/gr-qc/9808004v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/gr-qc/9808004v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="gr-qc" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="gr-qc" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1211.1557v1</id>
    <updated>2012-11-07T14:20:48Z</updated>
    <published>2012-11-07T14:20:48Z</published>
    <title>Scalar torsion and a new symmetry of general relativity</title>
    <summary>  We reformulate the general theory of relativity in the language of
Riemann-Cartan geometry. We start from the assumption that the space-time can
be described as a non-Riemannian manifold, which, in addition to the metric
field, is endowed with torsion. In this new framework, the gravitational field
is represented not only by the metric, but also by the torsion, which is
completely determined by a geometric scalar field. We show that in this
formulation general relativity has a new kind of invariance, whose invariance
group consists of a set of conformal and gauge transformations, called Cartan
transformations. These involve both the metric tensor and the torsion vector
field, and are similar to the well known Weyl gauge transformations. By making
use of the concept of Cartan gauges, we show that, under Cartan
transformations, the new formalism leads to different pictures of the same
gravitational phenomena. We show that in an arbitrary Cartan gauge general
relativity has the form of a scalar-tensor theory. In this approach, the
Riemann-Cartan geometry appears as the natural geometrical setting of the
general relativity theory when the latter is viewed in an arbitrary Cartan
gauge. We illustrate this fact by looking at the one of the classical tests of
general relativity theory, namely the gravitational spectral shift. Finally, we
extend the concept of space-time symmetry to the more general case of
Riemann-Cartan space-times endowed with scalar torsion. As an example, we
obtain the conservation laws for auto-parallel motion in a static spherically
symmetric vacuum space-time in a Cartan gauge, whose orbits are identical to
Schwarzschild orbits in general relativity.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>J. B. Fonseca-Neto</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>C. Romero</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>S. P. G. Martinez</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:doi xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">10.1007/s10714-013-1553-6</arxiv:doi>
    <link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10714-013-1553-6" rel="related"/>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">28 pages. arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1201.1469</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1211.1557v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1211.1557v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="gr-qc" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="gr-qc" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>

